good evening ladies and gentlemen
a very warm welcome to ICICI Lombard
General Insurance company limiteds Q2
and H1 f523 earnings conference call
from the Senior Management we have with
us today Mr bhargav dasgupta MD and CEO
of the company
Mr gopal balachandran CFO and cro
Mr Sanjeev mantri executive director
and Mr alak Agarwal executive director
please note that any statements comments
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management
and do not constitute an indication of
any future performance as future
involved risk and uncertainties which
could cause results to differ materially
from the current views being expressed
as a reminder
all participant lines will be in the
lesson only mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes
should you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star then 0 on your
Touchstone phone
please note that this conference is
being recorded
I now have the conference over to Mr
bhargav Das Gupta MDM CEO ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited thank you and
over to you sir
thank you and good evening to each one
of you thank you for joining the
earnings conference call of ikclumber
General Insurance Company Limited for
the second quarter and a half year of
fy23
I will give you a brief overview of the
industry Trends and developments that we
are we have witnessed in the last few
months post this RCA Focus will share
the financial performance of the company
for the quarter and half year ended
September 30 2022.
domestically the economic activity has
been Gathering fees and the recovery is
evidenced by the The High Frequency
indicators in the industrial under
Services sector
the Improvement in consumption spending
is expected to be sustained by strong
festive demand and possible Improvement
in rural consumption in the second half
of the year
the systemic credit is quite robust and
broad-based
in time headwinds from geopolitical
tensions tightening Global Financial
conditions strong dollar and elevated
Global inflation is slowing Global
demand resulting into lower Imports
which may have an adverse impact on
economic Indian economic growth in the
near term
as for the data published by CM the new
vehicle sales with this strong growth
for Private Car segments amidst easing
supply chain constraints and festive
demand the commercial vehicle segment
grew robustly supported by underlying
demand while the two wheeler segment
continued to remain low compared to the
pre-pandemic levels
health insurance continued to drive the
overall industry growth
the commercial lines witnessed growth in
line with the current market environment
we remain optimistic that the industry
will continue to grow given the lower
Insurance penetration positive consumer
sentiment and enhanced risk awareness
as a result the GI industry delivered a
gdpi growth of 15.3 percent for the
first half of this year over the first
half of last year
excluding crop insurance this growth is
at 18 for the same period
however we continue to see pricing
regression in certain segments like
motor
while there is some improvement in group
health segment for motor business
combined ratio for the industry was
124.5 in order one of my credit three as
compared to 107.1 for world one of fy22
as for public disclosures overall the
combined ratio of the industry improved
from 11 11.4 in quarter one of 2023 as
compared to 124.0 in quarter one of
2022.
in the recent past the authority has
announced several reforms to increase
Insurance penetration in the country
during the quarter The Authority has
issued and proposed following changes
one the exposure draft for an extensive
management and payment of commission
regulations proposing an aggregate limit
at a company level
two Master guidelines on AML including
kyc requirements along with establishing
internal policies procedures controls
and compliance Arrangements effective
November 1st 2022
number three increase in the number of
tie ups from three to nine in case of
corporate agents for each category of
insurance
number four other four forms of capital
wherein insurers can raise Capital by
way of reference shares or subordinated
debt without having to Avail prior
approval of the Authority number five
amendments to the regulatory sandbox the
sandbox regulations eliminating time
limit to facilitate innovation in
products or Solutions
and to increase the experimental period
up to 36 months these are all under
consideration and we believe that these
and many other changes have been made or
are being proposed which will have a
significant positive effect on product
Innovation ease of doing business and
insurance penetration
moving to business impact for us during
the quarter the company grew by 22.6
percent as compared to the industry
growth of 15.3 percent
coming to the growth of key segments
during the quarter
in motor growth remains different at 4.5
percent we continue to combat challenges
like heightened competitive intensity
the motor won't damage side we remain
focused on growing our market share in
certain key profitable sub segments
within motor overall new vehicle scenes
have been strong and demand sentiment
also continues to be positive
we are optimistic that with the
improving pricing environment we will be
able to consolidate leadership position
given our strength of distribution in
the segment
our investment in retail Health
distribution resulted in growth of 15.8
percent as against eight point zero
percent quarter one of five by twenty
three within the quarter we have
outgrown the industry and Standalone
players for the month of September with
the growth of 21.1 this was driven by
growth of business scores by regional
health agency vertical of 30.7 in the
quarter two of fi 23.
I would also like to share that our
One-Stop One-Stop solution for all
insurance and wellness needs I'll take
care as surface 2.7 million user
downloads till date the incremental
download for the quarter was 1 billion
our bank issues and key relationship uh
grew at 36.1 percent this quarter within
this its a Bank distribution grew at
33.9 and non-ic Bank distribution grew
by 37.6 percent
post pandemic the recovery in credit
along with the increase in volunteer and
distribution Partners acquired through
the demerger has been the pgo growth
driver
our business source through our digital
one team grew by 24.5 percent
overall our digital Focus has enabled us
to increase our digital revenues from to
uh 2.26 billion rupees which happens for
about 4.4 percent of our overall gdpa
for the quarter
as for the As far as the commercial
lines are concerned we experience
Rover's growth driven by 26.9 growth in
the SMA segment
we remain on track and are focused on
growth levels such as launching new
products strengthening our distribution
engine digital enhancements realizing
Synergy rationalizing cost wise carrying
up our preferred lines of business I
will now require to take you through the
financial numbers for the Recently
concluded quarter
good evening to each one of you uh I
will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the company
for Quarter Two and H1 FY 2023
the results presentations are already
put up on the stock exchanges and we are
in the process of putting up putting it
on the website of the company you can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers
the gross direct premium income of the
company was
at 105.55 billion in H1 f523 as against
rupees 86.13 billion in H1 f522 a growth
of 22.6 percent
this growth was higher than the industry
growth of 15.3 percent
GDP was at rupees 51.85 billion in Q2
f523 as against rupees 44.24 billion due
to FY 22. the growth of 17.2 percent
this growth was higher than the district
growth of 10 percent
or gdpi growth was famous primarily
driven by growth in preferred segments
the overall GDP of our Property and
Casualty segment grew by 16 at rupees
32.13 billion in H1 f523 as against
rupees 27.69 billion in H1 f522
on the retail set of the business the
GDP of the motor segment was at rupee
37.09 billion in H1 F by 23 as against
rupees 32.46 million in H1 F5 22
registering a growth of 14.3 percent
our agents which included which include
the point of sale come for the first
time
crossed one lakh to one lakh 636 as on
September 30 2022 from 94 559 as on June
30 2022.
as against
33.68 billion rupees as at March 31 2022
resultantly the combined ratio of 104.6
in H1 Empire 23 that's against one one
four point three percent in H1 fy22
excluding the impact of cyclone and
blood losses of rupees 0.28 billion the
combined ratio was 104.2 percent in H1
fy23 as against hundred and thirteen
percent in h1f by 22 excluding the
impact of cyclone and fluid losses off
which is 0.82 billion
excluding the impact of Blood and
Cyclone losses of rupees 0.28 billion
the combined ratio was 104.3 percent in
q2fy 23 as again 103.7 in Q2 fy22
excludes that again excludes the impact
of cyclone and fat losses rupees 0.5
million
our investment ethics Rose to rupees
400.96 billion as a September 30 22 from
398.34 billion as at June 3022 the
investment leverage debt of borrowings
was 4.08 times
on a quarterly basis investment income
increased to rupees 7.39 billion in q2fi
23 as against rupees 7.16 billion in Q2
f522 investment income of quarter to
f523 includes impairment on Equity
investment assets of RS 0.89 billion as
per the company policy
our capital gain net of impairment on
Equity investment assets stood at rupees
1.43 billion in H1 fy23 as compared to
rupees 4.71 billion in H1 FY 22. capital
gains net of impairment on Equity
investment Assets in quarter to fy23 was
lower at rupees 1.11 billion as compared
to rupees 1.44 billion in quarter to
fy22
our profit before tax grew by 26.1
percent that rupees 10.75 billion in H1
fy23 as against rupees 8.52 billion in
H1 fy22
whereas profit before tax
grew by 2.7 percent rupees 6.1 billion
in quarter to fi 23 as against rupees
5.9 billion 94 billion in q2f522
consequently profit after that grew by
46.6 percent
at rupees 9.40 billion in H1 FY 23 as
against 56.41 billion H1 f522 whereas
profit of attacks grew by 32.2 percent
at rupees 5.91 billion in Q2 fy23 from
now rupees 4.47 billion in quarter to FY
22. profit after tax for future 523
includes reversal of tax provision of
rupees 1.28 billion excluding this
growth in profit after tax was 26.5 and
3.4 for H1 and Q2 FY 23 respectively
return on average Equity was 19.9 in H1
f523 as against 15.2 percent in H1 f522
the return on equity for Fort Quarter
Two fy23 was 24.5 percent as against 21
in quarter to f522 excluding the
reversal of tax provision
the return on average equity for H1 and
Q2 fy23 was at 17.3 and 19.3 percent
respectively
so obviously ratio was at 2.47 times as
at September 30 22 as against 2.61 times
rather June 30 22 continued to be higher
than the regulatory minimum of 1.5 times
the board of directors of the company
has declared interim dividend of rupees
4.5 per share for H1 FY 22 degrees
the company has exercised a call option
to redeem the debentures of rupees 2.20
billion in full along with the final
interest due course received of
necessary regulatory or statutory
approvals on June July 7 2022. the
recorded for the same was August 7 2022
thus the outstanding debenture stands
that rupees 0.35 billion as like
September 30 2022 as I conclude I would
like to regulate we continue to stay
focused on profitable growth sustainable
value creation and safety interest of
quality holders at all times
I would like to thank you for attending
this earnings call and will be happy to
take any questions that you may have
thank you
thank you very much sir
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on your Touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star into
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
the first question is from the line of
swarnam Mukherjee from bnk Securities
please go ahead
yeah hi uh thank you for the opportunity
sir uh yes I have three questions first
of all uh the flow through from uh gross
written premium to my current premium so
I can see that there have been uh
sequentially higher retention level
during the quarter
and also seems really there's some uh
unexpired risk reservatives
if you could highlight what experiences
so the gdpi mix shows that there is a
higher share of private Vehicles again
um if you could throw some light up what
is going on there and what is the reason
behind the TP loss ratio the outcome
issue and thirdly on the crop crop
portfolio so we have reached at 800
crore kind of a number in first half I
think uh you had mentioned earlier that
you want the Run rate of what uh txle I
used to do in crops so does that mean
that there would not be any further
premium inflows in crop uh going ahead
in the second half so these are the
three questions sir
uh thank you let me take the third
question and I'll ask gopal to answer
the first and we'll jointly will be
handle the second
um on the crop business it's a seasonal
you know mix kharif is usually bigger
and the point that we had made earlier
was that crop business will remain about
five five plus minus five percent of our
of our portfolio I don't think there's
going to be any change in that so second
half of the year the amount of problems
will be significantly lower than this
number that you see in the first half
again the principle that we are
following is the business that came from
Veggie which had a Serial commitment
that we are maintaining
and apart from that uh the new business
that we've written is largely on the or
entirely on the 1810 model certain
States as you know have shifted to 1810
model where the cost of reinsurance for
us is significantly lower because of the
national uh limit of loss at 110 so
that's what we have written but the mix
of the business will be uh you know will
be much more in the first half compared
to the second half overall guidance that
we had given in terms of composition of
the mixer portfolio that doesn't change
I think there are a couple of uh
elements in that one is sequentially Y
is the retention ratio higher so if you
look at I think uh quarter one typically
is the period of commercial policy
renewal where the extent of reinsurance
support are relatively higher and that's
the reason why you find quarter one
detergent ratios to be relatively lower
than Q2 Q2 is more a book where you also
get to see the highest proportion of
retail business coming through and hence
to that extent sequentially is why you
find the retention ratios for Quarter
Two to be higher than water one
otherwise in that sense there is is
largely to do with the kind of distress
mix that we have for Q2 relative to q1
so your second point on uh in in terms
of our next fight risk Reserve releases
being slightly elevated I think that
primarily again a function of so again
no change in the way we kind of earn
revenues it's over the period of the
contract as one of your questions was in
the context of prop booking given the
fact that Curry's season typically has a
shorter time cycle when it comes to
earning of revenues and as to that
extent you will obviously find an
elevated levels of earnings coming
through in Quarter Two having said that
obviously you also kind of given the
fact in line with what you're explaining
in so far as the loss experiences are
concerned unless until we don't have the
complete estimate of the claims
experience till that point of time we
obviously continue to provide for losses
at 100 of the the earnings that has
happened so that's primarily the reason
why you get to see uh slightly elevated
earnings as compared to let's say maybe
the relative period that you're looking
at on the motor uh let me maybe take it
uh you know the mix of the business is
in line with what we had indicated at
the beginning of the year and in the
last conference call uh you know I don't
know where you've got this point about
private car increasing actually come
down if you look at last year first half
private car was about 56.5 percent of
our mix as we speak for this year first
half uh 56.5 percent this year is about
49.6 percent the increase is largely in
TV uh two wheeler is similar almost
every 26.5 has gone to 27.1 percent and
CV has increased from 17.1 percent to
23.4 percent in line with what we had
been saying for the last couple of
quarters the TV mix will be uh you know
in the mid-20s range so given the launch
dynamics that we are seeing in the
private car particularly particularly
private car motor OD is We Believe
significantly underpriced at this point
in time we've been a bit more cautious
on the private car segment and any case
as part of our strategy of increasing
our very selected TV business that that
strategy is playing out and if you see
the growth of CVS we have a very good
goal for the first half the CV business
has gone on about 56 for us this first
half
so just to follow up on that uh
very good
yeah so uh actually uh in terms of the
meat I was talking about what had
happened sequently so in q1 I think the
previous was
47.7 and in the first half it was 49.6
so from that point of view I was asking
whether you know you are seeing more
directional private Vehicles yeah I
understood your little q1 yes but if you
again compare with U2 to Q2 last case
and you have to look at you know YY
numbers because of seasonality their
festive periods where private car does
more uh so if you look at last year Q2
we had about 57 of weeks coming from
private card this year is 51 percent in
spite of the time that we uh festive
season has been a bit Freeport so
actually the clock relative drop is even
higher
hello okay okay got it yes
your last question on with respect to
motor third party loss ratios again
fundamentally as we keep saying you
should look at loss ratios more in the
context of let's say uh year-to-date
numbers are actually full year numbers
particularly for most of that party
given that it's a long tail line of
businesses in in a particular quarter
there are various
elements that goes goes into it uh we
would continue to reiterate that you
have to look at the portfolio experience
more on a year to date or as I said more
on a financial aid basis
okay so I've got it thank you thank you
sir uh that's all from my face
thank you thank you the next question is
from the lineup price Jain from motilal
oswal please go ahead
yeah hi hi everyone uh just a few
questions on my side first is on the
health claims Health claim ratio they
have increased significantly on a
sequential basis uh so could you break
it down as to what was the reason uh
secondly uh could you throw some light
on the implementation of vehicles act
and how how is it standing out across
the country and do we see some benefits
of it coming down coming in the news in
in the next couple of quarters or it's a
more driven one from an extra
perspective how do we see that happening
and lastly uh the could you cite the
reason for the dip insolvency or no uh
on a sequential basis that would be good
so maybe let me take this last part
first the decline in the solvency is
purely a function of what kind of growth
rates that you see and the mix of
business that you write
um so as I said I think Quarter Two
generally tends to be a portfolio mix
which is relatively more also in favor
of retail and as per the current Factor
based solvency regulations that are in
place the relative Capital requirement
for a retail business is far higher than
let's say the commercial line of
businesses so hence that's purely a
function of what kind of business volume
that you write but otherwise if you see
I think we are quite comfortable with
the level of solvency that we are
operating at which is about
2.47 times the second element what you
also look at uh in terms of impact on
solvency I think this is something that
you will get to see more or less in
every quarter two is uh post I mean we
declare dividends so far as final
dividend declarations happen towards the
end of the year which gets confirmed
that the AGM and the payment happens in
Quarter Two And So to that action there
is also an outflow on accounts of
dividend payout which tends to have an
impact in so far as solvency numbers are
concerned so otherwise it's a minor
sequential decline but these are the two
key factors is with respect to solvency
outcomes to your first point on the loss
ratio number I think when you look at
health for example
the loss ratios for the corporate book I
am giving you quarter two numbers
quarter to FY 23 numbers
the corporate or let's say the employer
employer loss ratios are at about 99.1
percent and the retail Indemnity numbers
and that
broadly the kind of uh range that we
have spoken about on the corporate
Hillside and or retail has Indemnity I
think the loss ratios for Quarter Two is
at about 64.4 percent
thank you
so the benefit also is kind of
relatively profitable so hence I think
this is within our acceptable levels of
loss number
only
um
book uh sequential increase in the loss
ratios can be attributable to what
factors because uh the intensity or is
it Monsoon related or uh what what would
be the factors about dry driving
increasing sequentially
so there are some seasonality impact of
uh you know Monsoon and uh you know
medical acute cases you know the the
Dengue malaria and also there's usually
a spike that we always see in this
period uh so and the second point about
sequential is that the previous quarter
there could have been some releases that
we got in that quarter uh but overall
the number is not going to be as high as
as the number that gopal talked about
for the whole year our senses that group
and this is the group of the employee
employee not the uh B2B to see the bank
of business is separate but the group
employer employee loss ratio will remain
in the uh you know ballpark number that
we had indicated which is you know in
the mid 90s uh for the year as a whole
what we are also seeing is that uh even
as we speak on a on a base if you
remember last year we used to talk about
the fact that we had to ask for we had
gone back to our clients you know
corporate clients and taken price
increases uh premium for Life had
increased post covet uh and we you know
this year also on top of that we are
seeing some price increases so we are
quite comfortable with the group health
portfolio as we see it in just one
quarter number we may not be fully
reflected with the book that we are
writing
your last point on motor third party
again you know there are some early
signs but it's too early for us to call
uh you know we would want to watch this
for a couple of quarters before we take
a final view on whether the motor
vehicles act implicate impact is uh
Across the Nation we are seeing some
early signs here and there but that's
not uh it's too early for us to take a
call that it's a uh it's happened at a
national scale
thank you thank you so much
thanks
thank you the next question is from the
line of shriya Shivani from clsa please
go ahead
thank you uh sir I have two questions uh
first is on the
uh overall growth uh I wanted your
opinion on uh
how should we sorry how should we
building growth for the
full year given that for first half you
guys have grown at 23 and particularly
your health book I mean on month on one
basis you guys are writing 400 crores uh
that way so I want to understand how
sustainable this 23 is or particularly
the group sorry the health uh book of
400 crores per month is first is on that
second I wanted to understand maybe a
little bit better Insight on why is
there so much uh cyclicality or movement
in your uh investment yields between one
q and 2q like the quarterly move is
quite high if I see it over previous
years the quarters of previous years it
was in this um this wide so I wanted to
understand that as well foreign
that we've made on the agency
distribution we are beginning to see
that uh play through if you see as we
mentioned in our opening remarks the
agency retail health agency numbers are
picking up
Group Health we are seeing some
improvement in pricing uh some of the
large players who've been in the past
very aggressive
they're toning down their aggression on
pricing and getting a bit more
disciplined so even on a group as an
employer employee portfolio we are
seeing uh conversions at prices that we
we are comfortable with so I don't see
any constraint and the last thing on the
on the health side ICC bank has
restarted Distributing the indemnity
policy on the on the uh you know on the
on the home home site so that's why the
bank numbers are high and and the banker
overall numbers are also high for given
the tires that we've got through the
acquisition they are performing really
well and the credit uh you know
dispersals are higher so our attachment
business is also picked up so on the
health side we remain uh reasonably
optimistic and confident about
maintaining uh you know our performance
and growth motor actually you know as I
said you know Market has been over
aggressive and I don't believe it's
sustainable we are again seeing some
players uh recalibrate on the CV side uh
further as in reduced discounts and you
know improve increased prices uh we want
to see we are seeing quite a few players
taking similar decisions on the private
car side equally there are a few players
who are still aggressive so if pricing
aggression gets muted on the motor side
it may give us an opportunity to grow
even faster than what we've grown in the
in this quarter that you know again we
Will Be watchful but I don't see the
numbers going below the current growth
numbers so overall we remain reasonably
confident about the growth uh you know
crazy that you said uh I think the only
you know concern that we you know remain
uh in about the market is the pricing on
the motor on their website that is
something that you would want to watch
uh a bit closely
I got it understood
I think story is purely a function of
what kind of uh interesting environment
that you see in the market I think at
this point of time we are seeing an
increasing interest rate regime and
therefore to that extent you will
obviously find they used to kind of
fluctuate between periods so otherwise
it's purely a function of what kind of
mix of Investments that we are making
and largely to do with the interstate
environment that's operating so that
actually you will always find uh
cyclicality in terms of outcome so
that's one and secondly when you look at
the overall yield on the aggregate
assuming on the entire investment income
when you look at obviously it's a
function of both interest accruals as
well as capital gains and you will never
find uh evening of capital gains across
periods for example if you look at let's
say the half year numbers the capital
gains for let's say first half it's just
about 100 1.43 billion this uh this half
year this look at each one of the
previous areas at about 471 crores so
when you look at the yield on the
overall portfolio including the on a
realized basis and you will obviously
find fluctuating uh outcomes
but at this point of time when we look
at it from an overall portfolio
standpoint a higher increase higher
interest rate regime actually occurs
well in so far as our interest accruals
are concerned because typically when you
look at our overall investment income
breakdown on an average roughly about 70
to 75 percent of our investment income
is through accrual and typically on an
average balance 25 to 30 percent is
capital gains
is within quarters obviously there can
be cyclicality with respect to what he
actually is
okay okay I'll get back in the queue
thank you
[Music]
thank you the next question is from the
line of nidesh from investec please go
ahead
thanks for the opportunities uh the two
three questions firstly uh what is the
number of number on the sales that we
have done from the island take care you
shared that number last quarter what is
the number that we have achieved in this
product effectively the downloads that
we have done which have been done in on
the identity care app has been quite a
strong this quarter so how are we
driving that downloads are we uh you
know are we increasing any cost to to to
to make a customer download this this
app and then the second question third
is uh your commentary on the on the
competitive intensity that few players
have become are recalibrating that is on
motor TP or model OD segment uh that you
are seeing uh reduction in computer
intensity and if and what are your sense
that in by what time period we may start
seeing motor on damage competitive
intensity coming down uh given that it
has been quite intense for last couple
of years and lastly is there any comment
on the and on the management session
planning given that there is a
possibility of a cap on CEO 10 years of
15 years these are the key questions
let me get the last one out you know the
yes the exposure draft is there for 15
years it's an exposure graph if it
becomes a final regulation then
obviously something will have to be done
but we will wait for that exposure drop
to come through
the second question on aggression we are
as we mentioned I think the real problem
is in the OD segment I mean you know we
uh you know opening remarks we talked
about the overall combined ratio for
motor the combined ratio for motor only
is even worse than that so TP is
actually proving to be better at this
point in time
so the aggression is in certain segments
and aggression gets played out in terms
of since you can't do anything with the
TP price people you know kind of do
higher discounting in the OD or incur
higher cost in uh in getting that
business so the problem is more in the
OD side
the other question that you had on I'll
take care just to give you the uh so one
is the you know how we drive doing it
what we're doing is you know initially
if you remember I'll take your app was
largely set up to uh you know engage our
corporate customers what I mean by
corporate customers is the employees of
corporate customers so when we sell our
group health insurance policy it's a
policy sold to a corporate but the
health insurance is for the employees
and really there was hardly any
engagement with them so that was the
original uh you know uh thought process
where we launched it about a bit more
than two years back
as we speak today more than 50 percent
of the employees of our corporates have
downloaded the app and use that app uh
and that but this percentage has been
increasing quarter and quarter so that's
one uh you know area where how we
prevent this the second is you know
gradually we now you know putting a lot
of effort on the uh on the bank issuance
and the agency and the retail side and
there you know it is not as easy to you
know bring about change because there's
a behavioral shift and you know you're
working with Distributors and agents Etc
but even there we are seeing very good
traction uh largely because people are
seeing value in that engagement so so
overall there is uh you know there may
be some cost per it's not material but
overall we are driving it through uh
basically conversion you think about it
we have roughly over lasting we had
about 30 million policies that we sold
right so uh you know let's say 2.7
million download still gives us a lot of
randomized growth uh you know a lot of
those numbers may be small ticket or two
or policies but still we see that as an
opportunity so that's what we're driving
your last question on on sales sales is
something that we started only last year
so it's beginning to pick up and when we
talk about sales it's uh you know it
includes the renewals that people do on
their own on the app that number in q1
was about 9.8 crores that number has
grown roughly three times in this
quarter so it's become a 27 for forecast
for this quarter and for the month of
September it was about 10 crores so we
are seeing very very good question in
terms of adoption engagement even in
terms of the you know what we track
monthly average users daily average
users
so we are seeing very good traction with
with that app as originally as we had
talked about this being a potential game
changer for our engagement model with
customers
but the last question on investment deal
uh if I look at the accrual investment
deal it has increased almost 80 90 basis
point uh sequentially uh So at around
7.3 so going forward this will be the
base e lend it will continue to increase
right is that that's the right
understanding
how does the interest rate cycle play
out as I kind of mentioned an increasing
interest rate regime obviously occurs
well for us in so far as interest
accruals are concerned but equally you
should be mindful of the fact that
correspondingly to that exchange from a
master Market perspective on the 16th
book you will obviously have a master
Market negative
and therefore the ability of us to
possibly realize any amount of capital
gain you may not see that happening so
when I kind of wave that broad split of
let's say 70 75 interest approvals and
25 30 will be of capital gain that could
possibly see some kind of a change but
if this momentum of let's say interested
cycle sustains then from an overall as
close continue to approve from business
realization which would definitely help
in overall uh increase in the yield of
the boat yeah so maybe your point is I
mean right I mean the carry deal should
keep on increasing given the yeah it's a
very positive from a longer term
perspective but on a quarterly basis the
point that gopal is making on capital
gains that may play out uh you know
opposite of utilities
last two quarters have increased quite
significantly almost 130 basis point
while uh our tenure of the book is four
years and we were after opinion that it
will improve but it will improve slowly
but it has improved quite significantly
in those two quarters so I was trying to
understand there is no one-off in the
accrual link
s
the duration of the book is actually
kind of uh increased uh the duration at
March 22 was roughly about 3.96 years
that number at June was 4.4 years
when you look at September the duration
is at almost about 4.8 years
from Equity not from uh
if that is your question sure sure thank
you sir thank you that's it for myself
thank you the next question is from the
line of sanket Goda from spark Capital
please go ahead
yeah thank you thanks for the
opportunity the motor already lost ratio
at 74.3 uh so sorry to interrupt if we
can take the phone on handset
foreign
[Music]
policies are going to increase in the
contribution
are we seeing structurally higher loss
ratios in motor OT business going ahead
so the answer to your first question is
no because the contribution of those
policies is uh negligible as we speak so
that is I'm going to move the needle not
just now for a long period of time in
our in our estimate uh the second part
of a question in the long term what will
it do look logically what it should do I
will have to wait to see what happens is
to price risk more granularly for better
customers so if a better customer get a
cheaper price logically the not so good
customer should pay a higher price now
whether the second thing will happen or
not that time will tell but that is how
it should play out it should you know
give us more uh ability to price
appropriate I mean in the past we've
done secondary measures of driving
behavior right LCB and you know what not
this gives you ability to write based on
driving behavior and driving distance so
you should price uh your risk better
doesn't mean that it should overall
become cheaper for the whole category
okay got it sir and and second um uh see
the personal accent cover uh business
which is highly profitable has seen a
very strong growth when I look at one
age and second quarter number which is
even getting reflected in the uh uh uh
uh so in the banker Channel numbers what
you have mentioned is it just wanting to
understand said that this these numbers
are sustainable Beyond a 523 because
because these channels initially started
started doing business for us and and
therefore they delivered the growth and
and they just wanted to know the
sustainability of these particular
numbers the given given it has been very
strong
what we've been saying is that we create
uh you know this person is picking up q1
uh in the first first quarter we had a
base effect of the previous cs plus
quarter right uh you know that was the
second the Delta wave and the you know
the business numbers were very very low
uh last year first quarter so on that
beat the first quarter of this year
looks very very elevated so as a
percentage it may not sustain but in
terms of absolute terms yes we are
really reasonably optimistic there is a
system
okay so I and finally a fundamental
question if I look at a historical trend
for the industry as a whole uh the Arium
growth of the industry or or even for
your company is always being higher
compared to gdpi growth but but if you
look at the current year Trend it it is
almost the opposite because because GT
side growth is very strong but but am
growth somehow is struggling
so so because it's just eight percent
for on year-on-year basis uh for our
company so I just wanted to understand
uh uh what what is that Missing Link
which is not driving the alien growth uh
uh a compared to what we have witnessed
in the past
again is a function of uh let's say uh
what kind of business outcomes are you
operating at now at this point of time
circuit let's see if as you would have
seen and what we have been talking
through is that in so far as our
combined ratios are concerned I think it
is currently slightly at elevated levels
than what we would expect it to operate
at so for example you saw the numbers
for Q2 at let's say 105 105.1 half care
about 204.6 percent so hence to that
extent obviously the relative
acquisition to cash flows or elected
asset Center management will be
relatively lower so that's uh one
component that will be a function of
what you say relative to growth second
when you specifically look at in the
context of quarter two you will always
find the flows to the overall asset
Center management to be lower that
primarily it happens because as I
mentioned in response to one of the
earlier questions q1 is a period where
you see bulk bulk of the corporate
renewals taking place where you end up
getting the premiums in quarter one
however given that where I mentioned
also that the corporate book generally
tends to have a higher proportion of
reinsurance as per the reinsurance
arrangements those settlements takes
place in quarter two so bulk of the
outflows again happen in Q2 and hence to
that exchange and not just this quarter
two if you look at historically in any
of the quarter tools you will find
relatively the flows that get accruled
in so far as the overall investment book
is concerned to be lower so and and as
we kind of continue to improve in
bringing down the overall combined
ratios within acceptable threshold over
the next couple of years is what we have
indicated you should logically get to
see a higher proportion of foreign
book so that's the second component the
third in line with what we have
indicated I think relative to again what
kind of business leaks that you write
for example health as we indicated will
not have as much of a long tail of
clothes compared to let's say motor and
at this point of time I think in so far
as the motor book is concerned given the
relative competitive intensity that we
see in the market we are a bit cautious
our health is doing reasonably well for
us and hence that's also a function of
what kind of approvals that happens to
the overall effect Center management as
we get to see pricing into in motor over
the next little few quarters and growth
comes comes back then obviously you will
start seeing a relatively higher
proportion of approvals happening to the
overall effect Center management
please
before we take the next question a
reminder to the participants please
limit your questions to do a participant
for any follow-up may be requested to
rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line of
neeraj toshniwal from UBS India please
go ahead
hello
I think there have been some uh
uh have some players again started to
you know kind of become more competitive
uh and that is impacting or I want to
read about it
yeah so as as I mentioned uh you know we
are seeing some green shoots in CV we
are seeing some moderation from some
other you know some of the larger uh
traditional players
um in od we are seeing some of the
players now rationalize the aggression
however at the same time there are still
a few players who are very aggressive
our senses that this will not sustain
but you know that is the reason why
we've been saying that we are a bit
cautious in the own damage segment
got it so any any uh on ground Trends
because September for the industry was
also we uh
anything uh which has changed or just
one of uh one could think about it
so it's been the trend that we've been
talking about for a lot actually a
couple of years there's been aggression
but it's sustained I mean generally as
you know I think we've mentioned this
many times but generally we see this
admission tone down after about a year
year and a half this time it's sustained
probably because of the economic
benefits that people saw last year we
were probably expecting this to come
down you know as a moderate sooner this
year it's taking a bit more time but the
early signs are uh early signs are you
know quite quite better you know early
signs are positive so we are optimistic
with a second half will be uh a bit
better than what we've seen in the first
time
also in terms of Premium so how how
actually uh overall given the commercial
it's already doing well and this already
pick up in Hill uh what kind of growth
are we kind of internally uh thank you
guys have a full year okay
I think I answered that question earlier
you know my our sense is that visually
what we indicated at the beginning of
the year we given the optimistic that we
hired foreign
thank you the next question is from the
lineup Avinash Singh from MK Global
please go ahead
yeah hi good evening a couple of
questions uh first uh if I look at the
overall you know commercial lines
particularly you know uh the liability
that is quite profitable what you have
you seem to have lost markets here so
either Market has gone too fast and you
have been cautious so what is driving
sort of your Market your loss in that
highly profitable line that particular
liability uh so that's one and second uh
would be more on what is uh I mean again
the media reporting around this uh
uh considering that is in more targeting
uh Health particular retail of what uh
do you see some kind of a channel
conflict there the other question
so Avinash in terms of liability uh last
year uh there was launch of a product by
one company last year which uh
you know is classified as a liability
product which The Authority has now uh
asked the industry not to write so if
you look at our group uh as it is our
growth you know for uh for Q2 is roughly
about 36.4 percent so our business
continues to do well uh into the market
share it is only because of that you
know that one company is one product
which we believe right now is not uh
there in the market that's the that's
the reason that you are seeing market
share drop but the traditional liability
business which is profitable the one
that you're talking about that's
something that we continue to do well
and we are going and we remain number
one in uh you know in traditional
liability uh if you keep out this HCL
browser you're talking about uh your
second question was uh I didn't get your
second question Avinash if you can just
repeat your second one yes it's around
bhima sugam that uh you know the direct
distribution initiative that uh for
media report has only come uh so will
there be a channel conflict because I
mean this is I will try to reach uh you
know retail customers retail health is
something where you or anyone else Drive
business a lot through agency so will
there be some kind of a channel conflict
because I mean you need to have
differential pricing otherwise I mean
this device is kind of a you know
obtained from data a day one
so our sense is that this will be this
is something that the authority is also
very keen on so this will uh you know
pick up and take up and our senses are
it will actually increase the
penetration rather than creating Channel
conflict uh we will have to wait to see
what the governance of that uh entity
you know the understanding that we have
at this point in time is that it will be
a industry control controlled entity as
in the shareholding will be largely
distributed across the players with
maybe a technology partner who will also
have you know some some fake we'll have
to design the governance mechanism of
that entity and the products that go on
there we will have to see what goes
there and you know which which segments
of customers it focuses on overall we
believe it's a it's a great positive in
terms of uh creating greater awareness
because everyone will talk about it and
the fact that it's something that the
regulator is endorsing it should create
the fair approach to Distribution on
online that we've been kind of hoping
for and waiting for so we are quite
optimistic about this
okay accurately uh on motor TP losses so
there are three moving parts of course
you have seen three four percent Blended
price high or maybe in the CV maybe
higher second part of course you have
you know uh this motor vehicle act
implementation that probably is kind of
a reduced crowd and all and third part
would be of course in place and cleaning
place and that is typically Double B can
come you know already very extreme uh
score to Vertical as well so all these
three put together you sort of for your
trend for the first half series that you
are still seeing uh you know a lot of
movement or a scope for improvement
because ultimately at this point it's
estimated and you haven't typically very
very conservative what makes you feel
sort of was that okay the motor TV with
these three moving Parts is going to
improve
um I got the most of the part of what we
said I've been asked where I didn't
digest is the last line what do you
think that why do you think it lead to
was that the question
yeah so I'll say the price hike has
happened but it's muted but claim
inflation are way very strong I mean in
a motor TV particularly some extreme
claim Awards and then uh of course motor
vehicle act will have positive impact so
there are much
uh you know your motor TP kind of a
claims ratio for first half there is
Improvement uh so I mean because I mean
my claims uh uh yeah so my TLC paper is
typically doubled it closed level is so
what is a sort of for your view I mean
you are facing this uh to go down
if you look at last year uh and that's
what we are kind of integrated at the
beginning of this year uh to a similar
question if you look at last year our TP
loss ratio was 74 uh for half year it's
about 70.1 but it's better to look at
analyze number rather than just this
quarter 66.6 uh to give you a sense of
what we believe is a more you know
reasonably accessible number having said
that I think the point that you're
making in terms of game inflation you
know this is the point that we've always
been making and accordingly we've had
reasonably High claim inflation numbers
in our reserving we believe that a lot
of companies hold uh you know
significantly lower percentage of
inflation and you know in essence that
may be inadequate
um but we are quite comfortable with the
inflation number that we are holding
what we want to observe is the frequency
drops that we anticipate because of uh
because of the uh the the new motor
vehicle act that we you know earlier
responded to but the frequency drop we
have to watch for before we conclude
that it's actually come through and you
know the reduction in Florida that
you're talking about is coming through
my sense is that we'll give it some time
to to to develop for us to build
confidence and talk about a reduced
number uh I hope that explains you what
are the short term uh thinking is and
what we believe can happen in the long
term
thank you
the next question is from the lineup
anjuman Dev from ICICI Securities please
go ahead
yeah hi good evening and thank you for
the opportunity
my question was regarding the comment
that you made on the icsa bank
restarting uh some of the attachment
sales for a home alone so is this the uh
the kind of benefit product that uh you
know we used to sell earlier because
that was very profitable and used to
contribute a decent amount to our
Prospect if you could clarify on that
thank you so anchovan I mentioned that
it's an Indemnity product and it's not
just this quarter even last quarter we
had indicated that the bank had
restarted selling attachment of Health
indignity uh so that's where the growth
is very strong uh obviously the product
concept is very different from the
original benefit construct and
accordingly profitable profitability
will be very different
understood thank you
thank you
the next question is from the lineup
Deepika Mantra from JP Morgan please go
ahead
um thank you thanks sir for taking my
question so just following up on the
ICICI Bank uh a loan linked product uh
in terms of scale is there scope to go
back to the earlier scale of premiums
that were being done even with an
Indemnity product
look at an aggregate relationship with a
band there are many things that we do
right it's not it's not one product that
we sell with the bank so there is uh SME
business that we do with them there is
the corporate business that we would do
with them there is help businesses
across different lines be it attachment
or in terms of Indemnity that we do with
them uh in aggregate the relationship is
becoming has become bigger uh the reason
why we wanted to talk about the health
number that we talked in the opening uh
remarks was because this last year was a
a bit of a drag because the health
business the attachment business has
been stopped the point that we are
making is that the attachment business
has started though the product construct
is different from what it was last year
foreign
could you tell us a little bit about the
experience on a renewals that are coming
in from the older books so what would be
the renewal rate of uh older customers
uh and uh in terms of loss experience
between new and old customers what would
be the differential
gopal to give you the numbers before
that I'll just give you the contribution
since you asked a question about it can
we go back just to give you a sense of
the numbers in aggregate
ICC Bank contribution if you go to two
years back before they took that call
was over 5.9 last year it dropped over
5.3 percent even though that big
business which we Associated attachment
went away we build other we do other uh
other segments other product categories
for q1 this year sorry Q2 the sales
we're gonna over 6.1 percent for the
whole year it's about 5.8 percent so in
a sense for the half year we are back to
a similar number that we had in 2021 in
terms of contribution now obviously our
business has grown so ICS Advanced
business is also going with us coming to
your personal renewal so until on the
health renewal uh percentages uh that
number is that it ranges between 75 to
80 percent that's the kind of retention
that we get to see your other point on
what kind of street do we see in so far
as the loss ratios on the new portfolio
and the older portfolio on the new I
think the portfolio of ratio could range
again anywhere between 45 to 50 percent
and the old portfolio loss ratios could
range between 75 to 80.
someone last question uh yeah
I'm sorry
as you know helping memory
the next question is from the line of
durgesh pujara from mirabilis please go
ahead uh yeah hi thanks so I have three
questions first is that 48 of the gdpi
comes from broker Channel I think
couldn't find anything about number of
Brokers or how has been the growth uh on
the broker front so can you talk about
that
and also do we have a separate team
yeah so there are two two segments of
business where Brokers play and ignore
one is the motor business all the oems
uh that MISD business largely comes
through Brokers this could be an oem
controller OEM broker like marupi has
their own broking entity through which
you you get access to the river ships uh
or some of the uh oems work with other
Brokers but it's still a broken business
uh you know in terms of the business
coming through and how we reflect in our
numbers so one is the motor business
which is the OEM driven mi3 business so
that's one the second is the corporate
business uh corporate you know we one of
the few companies which has a direct
sales team so we have direct
relationship management teams which does
Business Development goes to corporate
but we all equally work with Brokers uh
particularly from the sne segment and
also for uh corporate uh corporate
customers now for the SME and for
corporate customers we have a separate
broken T which is dedicatedly looking at
the working Channel
thank you
ladies and gentlemen due to time
constraint we take that as the last
question
I now have the conference over to Mr
bhargav dasgupta for closing comments
over to you sir
thank you guys for staying up to listen
to us and let me wish you a wish all of
you a very Happy Diwali on the behalf of
the entire management team of Isis
number thank you and look forward to
interaction our interactions over the
over the quarter thank you so much thank
you ladies and gentlemen on behalf of
ICICI Al Lombard General Insurance
Company Limited that concludes this
conference we thank you all for joining
us and you may not